Michael H. Wheatman

3116 Carnegie Dr | State College, PA 16803 Phone: (215) 326-9809 E-Mail: michael.wheatman@gmail.com

Summary

I am a software engineer with five years of technology industry experience specializing in defense minded applications and systems. I possess a rigorous academic background and strong communication skills. I maintain full time employment as a researcher with a specialization on scalable distributed systems.

Experience

Research and Development Engineer II - The Applied Research Laboratory at Penn State

2019 - Present

- Carry out underwater autonomy research for US Navy undersea and surface drones.
- ARL UMAA Reference Implementation Lead Software Engineer
- UMAA IWG member

Software Engineer II - Raytheon Corp.

2015 - 2019

- Contributes to ongoing development of classified computer systems for US Government customers.
 Maintains Top Secret/SCI US Government Security Clearance.
- Deputy Team Lead
- YESNET East Region Director of Communications

Software Development Engineer Intern - Amazon AWS

2014

Worked in AWS Identity and Access Management building an internal registry designed to centralize and organize the metadata and development information for all AWS services and APIs.

Computing Support Assistant - Carleton College ITS

2011 - 2015

Worked to provide technical support to students, faculty, and staff of the College.

Education

Pennsylvania State University - Computer Science (MS - anticipated 2020)

2016 - Present

- Thesis: Standard Interfaces for Unmanned Autonomous Systems.
- GPA: 3.72

Carleton College - Computer Science (BA), Cognitive Science (minor)

2011 - 2015

- Served on Library and Information Technology College Governance Committee
- Thesis: Augmented Reality on Mobile Systems.

Skills

Cloud Computing Technologies, Full Stack Java Development, Agile Software Development, Python Development, Computer Security, Linear Regression Techniques, Distributed Systems Design and Development, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, SQL and NoSQL Database Systems